(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
大神ミオ たんじょうび3Dライブ
Ookami Mio 3D Birthday Live
はっ、ああー！みんな！
Hah, ahh! Everyone!
見てるー？
Are you watching?
大神ミオだよー！
It's Ookami Mio!
わああー！
Waaa!
見てるかー？見て、見てるー？
Are you watching? Look, are you watching?
お誕生日おめでとうありがとうありがとうありがとう！
Happy Birthday, thank you, thank you, thank you!
はい、というわけで、えー皆さんこんばんミオです。大神ミオです。
Alright, so, good evening to you all. It's Ookami Mio.
ということで今日は、うちの誕生日に、
So, for my birthday today,
えーライブに来てくれて本当にどうもありがとう。
thank you all so much for coming to the live show.
あ、つばちゃんもありがとう。メンバーシップもありがとう。
Ah, thank you too, Tsuba-chan. Thank you for the membership.
見てるよ見てるよ見てるよー。
I'm watching, I'm watching, I'm watching!
ありがとうということで、今日は歌ももちろん
Thank you. Today we'll have songs of course,
ライブということでね、あるんだけど、
since it's a live concert, but...
あのー、まー色んなね、ゲストが来て、
Um, various guests will be coming,
なんか知ら、起こる、事件が起こるみたいなんにでね、
and it seems like some kind of... incidents will occur.
よかったらちょっとみんな最後まで見ててくれたら嬉しいなって思います。
I'd be happy if everyone could watch until the end.
よろしくね！ういーういーういー。
Please enjoy! Wee, wee, wee.
はい。では早速ですけど、１曲目からスタートしたいと思います。
Alright. Let's get started right away with the first song.
１曲目、うちが大好きな曲です。
The first song is one that I really love.
プラチナ、歌わせていただきます。
I'll be singing 'Platinum'.
I am a dreamer...
プラチナ 作詞 岩里 祐穂 作曲 菅野 よう子
Platinum | Lyrics: Yuho Iwasato | Composition: Yoko Kanno
ひそむパワー
Hidden power
私の世界
My world
夢と恋と不安でできてる
Is made of dreams, love, and anxiety
でも想像もしないもの かくれてるはず
But there must be something hidden that I haven't even imagined
空に向かう木々のようにあなたを
Like trees reaching for the sky
まっすぐ見つめてる
I'm looking straight at you
見つけたいな
I want to find it
かなえたいな
I want to make it come true
信じる それだけで 越えられないものはない
Just by believing, there's nothing I can't overcome
歌うように
Like singing
奇跡のように
Like a miracle
想いが 全てを変えてゆくよ
My feelings will change everything
きっと
Surely
驚くくらい
To a surprising degree
I am a dreamer...
ひそむパワー
Hidden power
まだ見ぬ世界
A world yet unseen
そこで何が待っていても
No matter what waits for me there
もし理想と違っても 恐れはしない
Even if it's different from my ideal, I won't be afraid
鳥たちは風に乗り旅をしてゆく
Birds travel on the wind
今日から明日へと
From today to tomorrow
伝えたいな
I want to tell you
叫びたいな
I want to shout it out
この世に一つだけの 存在である私
I am the only one of my kind in this world
祈るように
Like a prayer
星のように
Like a star
ちいさな光だけど...
Though it's just a small light...
I'm a dreamer
ひそむパワー
Hidden power
私の世界
My world
もっともっと強くならたい
I want to become stronger and stronger
限界のない
With no limits
可能性がここにある
possibilities are right here
この手に...
in my hands...
It's gonna be your world
見つけたいな
I want to find it
叶えたいな
I want to fulfill it
信じる それだけで
Just by believing
越えられないものはない
there's nothing that can't be overcome
歌うように
Like singing
奇跡のように
Like a miracle
思いが全てを変えていくよ きっと
my thoughts will surely change everything
きっと
Surely
驚くくらい
to a surprising extent
というわけでプラチナでした！
And so, that was Platina!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
はー、ちょっと、あの、久しぶりのライブなのでちょっぴり緊張したけれども...
Phew, well, since it's been a while since my last live performance, I was a little nervous...
あの、頑張って歌えたなって思います。
but I think I did my best singing.
はい、でもね、こっからは実は一人じゃないんです。
Yes, but from here on out, I'm actually not alone.
いろんな人がゲストに来てくれるって聞いてるんだけど...
I've heard that various people will be coming as guests...
次の曲は誰が来てくれるのかなー？
so I wonder who will join me for the next song?
うにょうにょ...
Wnyo wnyo...
え？この声は？この声は誰？
Eh? This voice? Whose voice is this?
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
すごいおっきいケーキだー！
Wow, it's a huge cake!
ケーキだぞー！
It's a cake!
持ってきましたー！
We brought it for you!
えー、ありがとう！嬉しい！
Eh, thank you! I'm so happy!
おめでとうだぞー！
Congratulations!
すごい、え、こんな美味しそうなケーキ、みんなで食べるために持ってきたんでしょ？
Amazing, eh, you brought such a delicious-looking cake for everyone to eat, right?
え、何そのテンション
Eh, what's with that attitude?
そうなんですけど、いや、ミオちゃんのためだよ
That's right, but no, it's for Mio-chan.
食べよう食べよう
Let's eat, let's eat.
あ、今日は簡単には食べられません。
Ah, today you can't eat it so easily.
食べられません？
Can't eat it?
ここで、白上クイズー！イエーイ！
Here comes the Shirakami Quiz! Yay!
ちょっと待って、うち誕生日なのになんかすごい特権がない...
Wait a minute, it's my birthday, but I don't seem to have much privilege...
なんで？
Why?
この白上クイズに答えられたら、食べることができます。
If you can answer this Shirakami Quiz, you can eat it.
ちょっと待って、白上、いつも打ち上げめちゃブリしてること怒ってる？
Wait a minute, Shirakami, are you mad about the unreasonable demands I always make at after-parties?
怒ってないよ。怒ってない。
I'm not mad. I'm not mad.
そういうことじゃない。
It's not about that.
なんだ、恨みつらみがあるのか？はっきり言え！
What is it, do you have a grudge? Say it clearly!
ないよ！
I don't!
嫌がらせだよー！
It's harassment!
お誕生日の嫌がらせ！
Birthday harassment!
クイズにも答えられたら食べれます。
If you answer the quiz, you can eat.
もし答えられなかった場合は...
If you can't answer...
あやめちゃんが食べます。
Ayame-chan will eat it.
イエーイ！余が食べちゃうよ！
Yay! I'm gonna eat it!
なんぜ！
Why!
よし、余の食べるフォークを召喚するなり。
Alright, I'll summon my eating fork.
テーン！ハッ！
Ta-da! Hah!
答えられたらあやめちゃんが「あーん」してくれるそうなのでね。
If you can answer, Ayame-chan will feed you, saying "Aa-nn".
え、余が「あーん」しちゃいます。
Eh, I'll do the "Aa-nn".
食べたいなー
I want to eat it.
余、一個取っちゃっていい？
Can I take one piece?
いいですよ。
Sure.
じゃあちょっとこちら失礼させていただきます。
Then, excuse me.
お、召喚完了！
Oh, summoning complete!
欲しいか？欲しいか？これ食べたいか？
Do you want it? Do you want it? Do you want to eat this?
食べたい！食べたい！
I want to eat! I want to eat!
ケーキの匂いを嗅がせてやるんだ。
Let her smell the cake.
はふはふはふ...
Huff huff huff...
ね、こちら、クイズ成功したらね、余があーんしてあげますので。
Hey, if you succeed in this quiz, I'll feed you.
カロリーの塊、カロリー爆弾をあーんしますよ。
I'll feed you a calorie bomb, a lump of calories.
よろしいですか？
Are you ready?
よろしいです。
I'm ready.
じゃあ行きます。クイズです！デデン！
Then, here we go. Quiz time! Ta-da!
えーと、7月の24日25日どっちだったかな、日曜日にね...
Um, on July 24th or 25th, I'm not sure which, on Sunday...
毎週日曜日公開されてるホログラからの問題です。
it's a question from HoloGra which is released every Sunday.
公開されたホロぐらの話！
The Hologra talk that was released!
内容はですね、遅れた七夕でした！
The content was, a late Tanabata!
七夕回、遅れた七夕回ありましたね。
The Tanabata episode, there was a late Tanabata episode, wasn't there?
ありました！
There was!
じゃあ、そのホロぐら内で、一番最後に喋った白上のセリフはなんだ？
Well then, in that Hologra, what was Shirakami's very last line?
えっ？
Eh?
あ、なんか... え、来年も会おうね、みたいな感じだったっけ？
Ah, something like... eh, "let's meet again next year," was it something like that?
それでいいですか？
Are you sure about that?
ファイナルアンサーですか？
Is that your final answer?
いいですか？
Is it okay?
え、ちょっと、え、ひ、ヒント、ヒント、ヒント！
Wait, uh, h-hint, hint, hint!
ヒントは、何かに対してのツッコミでした！
The hint is, it was a comeback to something!
えー、じゃあ違うじゃん！
Eh, then that's wrong!
なんだったっけな... いや、見た、見た、これ見たんだよ！
What was it... no, I saw it, I saw it, I definitely saw this!
えーっと、なんか短冊に対してのなんか、やつだったような気がするんだけど...
Umm, I feel like it was something about a tanzaku...
えーっと、『この願い事でいいんかい！』みたいなやつ！
Umm, something like "Is this wish really okay?!"
不正解ー！
Incorrect!
残念でしたー。うちのケーキ...
Too bad. My cake...
余がケーキ食べちゃいたいと思います！
I think I'll eat the cake!
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
あー、おいしかったわー。
Ah, that was delicious.
いいケーキだからね。でっかいケーキ、最高だね。
Because it's a good cake. A giant cake is the best, isn't it.
もう、うちもケーキ食べたかったよ、これはー！
Geez, I wanted to eat cake too, this time!
残りのケーキは、じゃあ白上が食べます！
The rest of the cake, then, Shirakami will eat!
おい、一瞬ケーキが小さくなっていく...
Hey, in an instant the cake is getting smaller...
あー、食べちゃった。お腹いっぱいになったー！
Ah, I ate it all. I'm full now!
いや、腹ごしらえもしましたし、ライブでもしますか！
Well, now that we've had a meal, shall we do a live performance?
なんだこれ！なんだこの流れは！
What is this! What is this flow!
うち、ケーキ一口しか食べてないよ！
I only ate one bite of cake!
じゃあ食後の運動ということで...
Then, as exercise after a meal...
せっかくライブ来てくれたんだから、二人とも歌ってくれるよね？
Since you came to the live performance, both of you will sing, right?
やったー！踊りましょー！
Yay! Let's dance!
じゃあちょっと、ステージに付こうか。
Then, let's head to the stage.
この三人と行ったら、何ですか？ありますからね。
Going with these three, what is it? There's that, you know.
この三人と言えば、せーの！
Speaking of these three, one, two...!
百花繚乱花吹雪！
Hyakkaryouran Hanafubuki!
色付く想い、はせつな...
Colorful feelings are fleeting...
百花繚乱花吹雪
Hyakkaryouran Hanafubuki
パッと咲いて散った 花は終わりに、を告げてくる
Flowers that bloom and fall suddenly, signal the end
その時を待てど暮らせど 言葉進まず
No matter how much I wait for that time, words don't come
そっと触れてしまった 胸の内の温かさを
I softly touched the warmth within my chest
初めてのこの気持ちだけ 抱きしめていたい
I want to keep embracing only this first-time feeling
暁交わした約束は 本物だってきっと
The promise we exchanged at dawn, I'm sure it's real
信じてる
I believe
いろはにほへと、の、花に魅せられた少女たち
Girls enchanted by the flowers of the alphabet
あーはらりはらりはらり落ちる 花、共に舞い踊れ
Ah, falling fluttering, fluttering, fluttering, flowers, let's dance together
惑う世なれど 想い、言の葉に込めてみた
Though the world is confusing, I tried to put my feelings into words
誰も皆憧れる 浮世の理よ
The logic of the floating world that everyone yearns for
色付く想い、はせつな 百花繚乱花吹雪
Colorful feelings are fleeting, Hyakkaryouran Hanafubuki
フッと吹き消した 夜を灯す月明かりに
With a puff, the moonlight that lights up the night was blown out
曖昧な心が揺れて 声は響かず
My ambiguous heart wavers, and my voice doesn't ring out
もっと触れたくて 夢をなぞる指先さえ
Wanting to touch more, even my fingertips tracing the dream
いつの日か馳せた形を 忘れかけてた
I was starting to forget the form I once yearned for
浮世の波にたゆたう時 うたかたの夢は
When drifting on the waves of the floating world, the ephemeral dream
弾けてく
Will burst
有為の奥山に...
In the deep mountains of existence...
…少女たちは純情
...the girls are purehearted.
そのらりくらり ここからゆらめき歌うわ切磋
Wandering aimlessly, I'll flicker and sing from here, polishing my heart.
浅き夢見しと思ひ 踏み込むこの世界は
Thinking I've seen a shallow dream, I step into this world.
誰も皆 焦がれる
Everyone yearns for it,
現世の理よ
the logic of this ephemeral world.
色付く想いは切な 百花繚乱花吹雪
My coloring feelings are painful—a riot of flowers, a blizzard of petals.
秘密数えて
Counting my secrets...
ここにおいで
...please come here.
暁 交わした約束は
The promise we made at dawn,
本物だと きっと信じてる
I surely believe it's real.
いろはにほへと 華に魅せられた少女たち
Even as the flowers fade, the girls are enchanted by their beauty.
あはらり はらり はらり 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
Ah, gently, gently, gently, dance with the falling blossoms.
泡沫（うたかた） 袖（そで）でも想い 言の葉に込めてみた
Even if my sleeve is ephemeral, I've put my feelings into words.
誰も皆 焦がれる
Everyone yearns for it,
現世の理よ
the logic of this ephemeral world.
色付く想いは切な 百花繚乱花吹雪
My coloring feelings are painful—a riot of flowers, a blizzard of petals.
風に舞う 乙女の純情 咲き誇れ
Purehearted maiden dancing in the wind, bloom in full glory!
（歓声） 楽しかったー！
(Cheering) That was so much fun!
終わっちゃったー！踊りきったー！
It's over! We danced our hearts out!
2人とも、どうもありがとうね！
Thank you both so much!
いや、こちらこそ！
No, thank you!
ケーキまでご馳走になっちゃって、誘ってくれてありがとうございます！
You even treated us to cake. Thank you for inviting us!
お腹もいっぱいや。
I'm stuffed too.
お腹いっぱいになりました。
My stomach is full.
そ、そうか。それなら良かったんだが。
I-I see. I'm glad to hear that then.
ご馳走様でした！
Thanks for the treat!
でも、うちは百花繚乱花吹雪をこうやって3人で踊るのめっちゃ好きなの。
But you know, I really love dancing 'Hyakka Ryouran Hanafubuki' as a trio like this.
わかる、楽しい！いいよね！
I know, it's so fun! It's great, right?
そうなんだよ。もう一生懸命覚えたしさ、今でも覚えてるしさ。
Exactly. We practiced so hard to learn it, and I still remember it perfectly.
振り付けが合う時とかすごい気持ちいいんだよな。
It feels so good when the choreography syncs up perfectly.
今日は誕生日に2人に来てもらって、本当に嬉しかった。ありがとうね！
I'm so happy you both could come for my birthday today. Thank you!
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
まぁちょっとケーキは食いきられてしまったけれど…。
Well, the cake did get all eaten up though...
また買おう！また今度！
Let's buy more! Next time!
また別でお祝いするから。
We'll celebrate again separately later.
やった！それならよし！
Yay! Then that's fine!
ケーキパーティーしよ！
Let's have a cake party!
ということで、そろそろお時間らしいぞ。
Anyway, it seems it's about time.
我々はじゃあ、帰るか！
Shall we head back then?
えー！帰っちゃうのー！？
Eh?! You're leaving already!?
裏で見てるから大丈夫。
We'll be watching from backstage, so don't worry.
舞台袖から応援し合おう。
Let's cheer each other on from the wings.
賑やかしてくれても全然いいから！
You're welcome to liven things up anytime!
あ、そうだミオ、今日のミオのラッキースポットをさっき聞いてたんだった。
Oh, right! Mio, I heard about your lucky spot for today earlier.
ラッキースポット？
Lucky spot?
ラッキースポット、海らしいよ。
Apparently, your lucky spot is the sea.
海！？
The sea!?
海！？夏だしね。
The sea!? Well, it is summer.
海がすごい穴場らしいです。
Apparently the sea is quite the hidden gem.
海で打ち上げ花火とか見てみたいなぁ。
I'd love to see fireworks display at the sea.
いいねー！そんなことできるのかなぁ？
That sounds great! I wonder if we can do that?
夏だし見たいよね。
It's summer, so I definitely want to see them.
ということで、我々はちょっとお先に…。
Well then, we'll be heading off now...
おいとまいたすぜ。ありがとうね！
...we'll take our leave. Thank you!
おめでとう！バイバーイ！
Happy birthday! Bye-bye!
え、ラッキースポット海だって…。
Eh? My lucky spot is the sea...
でも他のメンバーもいるかもしれないから、ちょっと海に行ってみようかなぁ。
But since the other members might be there too, maybe I'll go check out the sea for a bit.
おおー、すごい星空！
Ooh, what an amazing starry sky!
ちょっとお祝いなので、海行きたいなーと思って、夏だし。海に来ちゃいましたー。
Since it's a celebration, I felt like going to the sea, and since it's summer... I've arrived at the sea!
あれ？あ、あれ？お、ミオちゃん。
Wait? Oh, wait? Oh, Mio-chan.
え！？あやめ！？どうした！？え、忘れ物？
Eh?! Ayame?! What's up?! Did you forget something?
ここ、スタジオじゃないよ！
This isn't the studio, you know!
あれ？なんか、あれ？なんでここ海なん？
Wait? Somehow, wait... why is it the sea here?
夏だから、うちが来たいなーと思って。
Since it's summer, I felt like coming here.
あ、夏。そういうことね。
Ah, summer. I see.
ワープしてきちゃったんだよ。
I just warped over here.
なんか、ミオちゃんとまだ歌いたかったなーと思いながら歩いてたら、なんか海に着いちゃったね。
I was walking while thinking about how I wanted to sing with Mio-chan some more, and somehow I ended up at the sea.
うちのことを思いながら歩いてたら、いつの間にか来ちゃった？海に。
You were walking while thinking about me, and before you knew it, you arrived? At the sea?
海に着いてました。
I arrived at the sea.
それって、てぇてぇってこと！？
Does that mean... we're 'Tee-tee'!?
ありがとー！
Thank you!
やったー！
Yay!
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
あれ？この曲...
Huh? This song...
なんか聞こえる。
I hear something.
なんか聞いたことある。
I've heard it somewhere before.
うん、なんだっけ？
Yeah, what was it?
え、じゃあこの曲二人で歌おうか？
Oh, then shall we sing this song together?
歌おうか！
Let's sing it!
え、二人で歌うの初めて！
Wow, our first time singing together!
楽しみだな！
I'm so excited!
打上花火
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Uchiage Hanabi
Lyrics/Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember that beach we looked out over that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
Words carved in the sand, and the sight of you from behind
寄り返す波が 足元をよぎり何かをさらう
The returning waves wash over my feet and take something away
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
In the evening calm, only the twilight passes by
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks bloom with a sudden flash
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
A summer that surely hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
It melted our ambiguous hearts and tied them together
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
あと何度君と同じ花火を 見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can see the fireworks with you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
I wonder what I can do for your smiling face
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動
Hurting, rejoicing, and the cycle of waves and emotions
焦燥 最終列車の音
Impatience, the sound of the last train
パッと息を飲めば 消えちゃいそうな光が
If I held my breath, the light seemed like it might disappear
きっとまだ 胸に住んでいた
It must still be living in my heart
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
The warm future I could touch if I reached out
密かに二人を見ていた
Was secretly watching the two of us
パッと花火が
Suddenly, fireworks
夜に咲いた
Bloomed in the night
夜に咲いて
Blooming in the night
静かに消えた
Quietly disappeared
離さないで
Don't let go
もう少しだけ
Just a little longer
このままで
Just like this
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember that beach we looked out over that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
Words carved in the sand, and the sight of you from behind
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks bloom with a sudden flash
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
A summer that surely hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
It melted our ambiguous hearts and tied them together
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
たまやー！
Tamaya~!
すごい！めっちゃ花火上がってる！
Amazing! So many fireworks are going up!
綺麗だねー！
It's beautiful!
きれー！すごい！
Beautiful! Amazing!
うわー、これ本当になんか、あははは。
Wow, this is really like, ahahaha.
忘れてた！忘れてた！
I forgot! I forgot!
あ、歌うの。あははは。
Oh, about singing. Ahahaha.
いやー、なんか二人で歌うの初めてだったけど...
Wow, it was our first time singing together but...
あー、すごかったよ、あやめちょっと、曲がちょっとジーンときちゃったよ。
Ah, it was amazing. Ayame got a bit emotional during the song.
あ、きちゃった？いいね、曲が夏らしい、すご。あやめちゃんと歌えて嬉しかったよ。
Oh, you did? That's good. The song was very summery, it was great. I was happy to sing with you, Ayame-chan.
いや、ありがとう、嬉しい！また一緒に歌いたいな。
No, thank you, I'm happy! I want to sing with you again.
うん、これからもまた歌おうね。お誕生日おめでとう！
Yeah, let's sing together again. Happy birthday!
ありがとう！あ、ありがとね。
Thank you! Ah, thanks.
うん、気をつけて帰るんだよ。こんなとこまで来ちゃったけど、一人でちょっと頑張って帰ろう。
Yeah, be careful on your way home. We've come all this way, but I'll try my best to get back by myself.
あー、なんかちょっと心配になってきちゃった。大丈夫？ちょっと帰ろうかな。
Ah, I'm getting a little worried. Are you okay? Maybe I should head back too.
水上ボートで帰るから、水上ボートで歩いて。バイバイ！
I'll go back by water boat, walking to the water boat. Bye-bye!
頑張ってねミオちゃん！気をつけてねー！
Good luck Mio-chan! Take care!
あ、あやめ帰っちゃったな。
Ah, Ayame's gone home.
すごい花火だな。
What amazing fireworks.
きれい。
Beautiful.
おーい、ミオちゃーん！起きろー！
Hey, Mio-chan! Wake up!
ミオちゃーん、起きろー！
Mio-chan, wake up!
なんだ、なんかうるさい。
What... it's noisy.
起きろー！起きろー！
Wake up! Wake up!
起きろー！起きろー！起きろー！
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
起きろー！起きろー！
Wake up! Wake up!
起きた？起きた？
Are you awake? Are you awake?
起きたけど、な、何何？
I'm awake, but, what, what?
おはよー！おはよー！
Good morning! Good morning!
みんなどうしたの？なんでこんなとこにいんの？
What's wrong with everyone? Why are you here?
え、知らん。
Eh, I don't know.
なんかミオちゃんが海に落ちてたから。
Because Mio-chan was falling in the sea.
そうだよ、拾ったんだよ、拾ってあげたの。
That's right, we picked you up. We picked you up for you.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
生きてた。
You were alive.
よかった、死んでたらやばい。何でこんなとこにいたの？
Good, it would have been bad if you were dead. Why were you here?
いや、なんか昨日、え？なんか花火を見てて、あやめと一緒に歌ってたような気がするんだよな。
No, yesterday... eh? I feel like I was watching fireworks and singing with Ayame.
その後気絶して海に漂ってたってこと！？
Does that mean you fainted after that and were drifting in the sea!?
おー、そういうこと？やばいね、それ。なんか化かされたような気持ちだよ。
Oh, is that it? That's crazy. I feel like I've been bewitched.
あ, ほら、プレゼント買ってきたの！
Ah, look, we bought you a present!
お、プレゼント？いいね。
Oh, a present? Nice.
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-dah!
見て見て、スイカ買ってきたよ。
Look, look, we bought a watermelon.
スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！
Watermelon! Watermelon! Watermelon! Watermelon!
本人を差し置いてめちゃめちゃ喜んでんじゃん。
You're way more excited than the birthday girl herself.
夏だもんね、スイカ。
It's summer, after all. Watermelon.
みんなで食べる？
Shall we all eat it?
食べたーい！食べよう！
We want to eat! Let's eat!
せっかくだからさ、スイカ割りとかしない？夏の思い出に。
Since we're here, why don't we do some watermelon splitting? As a summer memory.
いいね！やろうやろう！
Great! Let's do it, let's do it!
誰が割る？
Who's going to split it?
え、あ、そりゃまあ、ちょっと尺がちょっと巻き気味で行かなきゃ。
Eh, ah, well, we have to keep things moving since we're a bit short on time.
尺？
Time?
じゃあ4人で同時にいっちゃう！？
Then, shall we all four go at once!?
同時に！？
At once!?
同時に！
At once!
おー、なんだこれ！都合のいい棒が、出てきた。
Oh, what's this! A convenient stick appeared.
じゃあね、これ4人で目隠しをして、危な、5回回ったと思ったら、スイカ割りに行こう。
Okay, so the four of us will be blindfolded—watch out—and once we think we've spun around five times, let's go split the watermelon.
5回回るの？
Five times?
うん。
Yeah.
オッケー、やってみたい。じゃあスタート位置からちょっと離れよう。
Okay, I want to try. Then let's move a bit away from the starting position.
あ、じゃあ、リハーサルやろうか、リハーサル。
Ah, then, let's do a rehearsal, a rehearsal.
うわ、なんか目が見えない！見えない！
Whoa, I can't see! I can't see!
ほらね、お前何ずらしてんだよ、ずるいぞ！
See, why are you shifting it? That's cheating!
ここでいいの。
It's fine like this.
よいしょ、よいしょ。よかったよかった。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Good, good.
くそー！
Damn it!
そうじゃないでしょ、準備はいい？
That's not it, are you ready?
じゃあちょっと、一回回らずにやってみようか、スイカ割れるかどうか。よーいスタート！リハーサル！
Then let's try it once without spinning to see if we can split the watermelon. Ready, start! Rehearsal!
やったー！割れた！
Yay! It's split!
すごーい！やったー！
Amazing! Yay!
やばい、とんでもない奴がいる。
Crap, there's a crazy person here.
なんかやばかったって今、割れてるよ。よかったー。
That was pretty crazy just now, but it's split. Thank goodness.
割れてるっぽい。
Looks split.
割れとるやないかい！
It's totally split!
じゃあちょっと、もう一回、じゃあ本番ということで。
Then, one more time, but this time for real.
わかった。
Understood.
さっきなんかドーンって爆発音がしたぜ。トーマスみたいのが来たよ。
I heard a booming explosion sound earlier. Something like Thomas came.
走り回ってたよね、何だったんだあれ。
It was running around, what was that?
じゃあちょっとじゃあみんな、スイカから若干離れた状態で、いきますよ、じゃあ5回回って。
Okay then everyone, stand a bit away from the watermelon. Here we go, spin five times.
5回回ったなと思ったらスタートだからね。はい目瞑って。いきますよ。よーいスタート！
Once you think you've spun five times, that's the start. Okay, close your eyes. Here we go. Ready, start!
1、2、3、4、5。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
いくぞー！
Let's go!
やったー！
We did it!
え？やった？
Wait, did we do it?
やったー！すごい！
We did it! Amazing!
すごーい！
Amazing!
ミオしゃ！
Mio-sha!
ころさん！大丈夫？
Koro-san! Are you okay?
大丈夫！
I'm okay!
終わったよ！
It's finished!
すごーい！
Amazing!
やったー！
Yay!
全然さ、たどり着けなかった。
I couldn't reach it at all.
なんかだって、終わったらおかゆそっちで...
Because when I finished, Okayu was over there...
...スバルそこにいたし！
...and Subaru was right there!
危ないよ！
That's dangerous!
やばい、本当わかんなかった。
Man, I really had no idea.
じゃあ、どうぞ！食べてください。
Well, here you go! Please eat.
じゃあちょっとスイカ食べちゃおうか、みんなで。
Then, shall we all eat some watermelon together?
たださ、このスイカ...
But you know, this watermelon...
...ちょっと切ったりとかもしたいし。
...I want to cut it properly and stuff.
一回さ、誕生日のケーキもあるからさ。
Also, we have the birthday cake too.
事務所に帰ってさ、休憩しながら食べん？
Let's go back to the office and eat while resting, okay?
いぇーい！
Yay!
じゃあ一旦事務所に戻っちゃおう！
Then let's head back to the office for now!
おっしゃー！いぇーい！
Alright! Yay!
スイカ、スイカ、スイカ、スイカ...
Watermelon, watermelon, watermelon, watermelon...
ケーキも、ケーキも、ケーキも...
Cake too, cake too, cake too...
ケーキ！スイカ！
Cake! Watermelon!
あれ？なんかある。
Oh? There's something here.
なんかゴミ落ちてるんだけど。
There's some trash lying around.
捨てとけよな、ゴミ。
Just throw it away, the trash.
本当だよ、ゴミ落ちてる。
Really, there's trash here.
ゴミでけぇ。
The trash is huge.
なにそれ？
What's that?
ゴミでけぇ。
The trash is huge.
ゴミでかくない？
Isn't the trash huge?
なに？
What?
「アイドルらしく可愛く歌えないと...」
"If you can't sing cutely like an idol..."
「ケーキとスイカはお預けです」って書いてある。
"...the cake and watermelon are withheld," it says.
ええー！？
Whaaat?!
取られてんじゃん！
They've been taken!
誰だよ！
Who did this?!
歌房無理だ。
Singing is impossible.
誰だよ！
Who was it?!
諦めないでよ！
Don't give up!
もう無理だ。
It's already impossible.
無理じゃないよ！
It's not impossible!
返してよこれ。
Give them back.
でもさ、可愛く歌えないとって言ったから...
But since it said if we can't sing cutely...
...可愛く歌えばいいんじゃない？
...we just have to sing cutely, right?
本当？
Really?
適当すぎない？
Aren't you being too casual?
ケーキ返してください〜！スイカ、スイカ〜！
Please give us back our cake! Watermelon, watermelon!
帰ってこないということは別にとという感じですね。
The fact that they're not coming back means it's not working.
そうですね。
That's true.
これは可愛い判定に引っかからないと。
This won't count as "cute."
でしょー。
Right.
はい、というわけでじゃあちょっと...
Okay, so then...
...「可愛い」は衣装から！形から行こうか。
..."cute" starts with the outfit! Let's start with appearances.
なるほど。
I see.
うちらの可愛い衣装、わかるよね？
You know our cute outfits, right?
もちろん！
Of course!
じゃあちょっと着替えちゃおうかな。いくよみんな！
Then I'll go change. Ready everyone?!
あー！
Ah!
せーの...
One, two...
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
いぇーい！どーだー？可愛い！
Yay! How's this? So cute!
可愛い、可愛いね。
Cute, so cute.
これでもう合格で...
Is this a pass...?
あれ？もう合格？
Huh? Already passed?
合格！合格！合格！合格！
Pass! Pass! Pass! Pass!
合格は？
Is it a pass?
あ、ダメだって。
Ah, they said no.
おい！なんでや！
Hey! Why?!
なんでやねん！
What the heck!
ダメだって出てこないことは。
Since they said no, it's not coming out.
無理だ...
It's impossible...
やっぱり歌わないとダメなんだよ。
We really have to sing after all.
あ、そうか。歌わなきゃいけないのか。
Ah, I see. We have to sing.
可愛く勝負しなきゃいけないんじゃない？
Don't we have to show off our cuteness?
ちょっとさ、じゃあ四人で歌う曲考えたいんだけど。
Wait, I want to think of a song for the four of us to sing.
え、ここで歌うの？
Eh, we're singing here?
え、まぁここにまぁジャッジする人がいるし。
Well, there's a judge here.
ここ？！
Here?!
なんか段ボールとかあるよ。
There are cardboard boxes and stuff.
本当だよ。せめてもうちょっと片付ければ...
Really. If we just tidied up a bit more...
ほら、なんかジェット機みたいなのあるよ。
Look, there's like a jet-looking thing there.
あれころねちゃんが買ったやつ。
That's something Korone-chan bought.
あ、マジ？ころねちゃん...
Ah, really? Korone-chan...
...買ってきたのか。
...bought that.
さ、そうだ！みんなさ、リスナーさんも知ってるし...
Wait, I know! Everyone, and the listeners too...
...多分四人とも知ってるかなと思う曲があるんだけどさ。
...I think all four of us know this song.
なに？
What is it?
「おちゃめ機能」って言うんだけど。
It's called "Ochame Kinou."
あー！知ってる！歌ってた！
Ah! I know it! We've sung it before!
それちょっと可愛いし、ちょっと四人で歌ってみない？
It's a bit cute, so want to try singing it as a foursome?
いいねー！いいよー！
Sounds good! Let's do it!
テテテテテテ...
Te-te-te-te-te...
早い早い早い！
Too fast, too fast!
まだまだまだ！ちゃんとBGMあると思うからね。
Not yet! I'm sure there'll be proper BGM.
アカペラかと思った。
I thought we were doing it a cappella.
それでは、「おちゃめ機能」いってみよう！
Now then, let's go with "Ochame Kinou"!
おっしゃー！
Alright!
じゃあポーズ！ポーズ！
Now, pose! Pose!
おちゃめ機能
作詞・作曲：ゴジマジP
Ochame Kinou
Lyrics & Music: Gojimaji-P
いつでも I love you 君に Take me kiss me
I'll always love you, give me a "Take me, kiss me"
忘れられないから 僕の大事なメモリー
Because I can't forget, my precious memory
どな焼きは主食になれない
Tonayaki can't be a staple food
ならば上書きしちゃえば 僕の思い通り
Well, if I overwrite it, then everything's as I wish
ずっとそばで見ているよ
I'm always watching by your side
バックアップは任せて
Leave the backup to me
左から右へ...
From left to right...
いつでも I love you. 君に Take 2 Kiss me.
Always, I love you. Take 2 kiss me for you.
忘れられないから 僕の大事なメモリー
Because I can't forget, my precious memory.
どら焼きは 主食になれない ならば上書きしちゃえば 僕の思い通り
Dorayaki can't be a staple food, so if I overwrite it, it'll be just as I want.
可愛いたしなみの音 合図で音速に
The sound of cute manners, reaching sonic speed at the signal.
触るなんて 気にしるからにきまってんじゃん
If you touch me, of course I'll be conscious of it.
それでも信じて 幸せになるように 礼儀正しく まずはささいな挨拶からから アイレニ
Even so, believe, so we can be happy, be polite, starting with a small greeting, 'Ai-re-ni'.
いつでも I love you. 君に Take 2 Kiss me.
Always, I love you. Take 2 kiss me for you.
忘れられないから 僕の大事なメモリー
Because I can't forget, my precious memory.
どら焼きは 主食になれない ならば
Dorayaki can't be a staple food, so...
上書きしちゃえば 僕の思い通り
...if I overwrite it, it'll be just as I want.
夢からピピピさめないで さめないで ぬくもり逃げないで
Please don't wake up from the dream, don't wake up, don't let the warmth escape.
まだあと５分 いや１０分待たせて
Wait for another 5 minutes, no, 10 minutes.
１００年後続くなら 約束圧縮して
If it continues for 100 years, compress the promise.
待ち構えるから 勘違いのテキパキテキ
Because I'll be waiting, a misunderstanding 'tekipaki-teki'.
ストローの加え方 少しは違うでしょう
The way you hold the straw is a bit different, right?
見て見ぬふりされた 世界が爆発しちゃう
Ignored by everyone, the world is going to explode.
助手席に乗り出す でもすぐに凹みだす 可憐な暴走 誰か止めてよ
Lean out of the passenger seat, but immediately get depressed, a lovely rampage, someone stop it.
待って待ってベイベー ぶつかればまた新しい 知識発掘
Wait wait baby, if we collide, it's new knowledge excavation,
でも力尽きてしまえばそこまで オーマイガー
but if I run out of strength, that's it, Oh My God.
いつでも I love you. 君に Take 2 Kiss me.
Always, I love you. Take 2 kiss me for you.
お星様に願い事 叶えてくれますか
Will you grant my wish to the stars?
地球の裏側まで 僕を運んで 一番綺麗な 花探しに行くんだ
Carry me to the other side of the earth, I'm going to look for the most beautiful flower.
まだ君の熱い想いは 想いは 頬に伝う涙
Your hot feelings are still, the tears running down your cheeks.
雫は胸に包んで 届けるよ 空に
I'll wrap the droplets in my heart and deliver them to the sky.
イエーイ！
Yay!
フー！
Whoo!
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
どっかー可愛い！
So cute!
可愛い！
Cute!
宇宙一可愛い！
Cutest in the universe!
お誕生日！
Birthday!
ケーキも吸い込んじゃうからね！
I'll even inhale the cake!
ヤッホーー！
Yahoooo!
お腹空いた！
I'm hungry!
そろそろ始まるんじゃない？
Isn't it starting soon?
オスバで行くぞー！
Let's go with O-Suba!
ラストスパート行くぞ！
Let's go for the last spurt!
いつでも I love you. 君に Take 2 Kiss me.
Always, I love you. Take 2 kiss me for you.
地球の裏側まで 僕を運んで 一番綺麗な 花探しに行くんだ
Carry me to the other side of the earth, I'm going to look for the most beautiful flower.
まだ君の熱い想いは 想いは 頬に伝う涙
Your hot feelings are still, the tears running down your cheeks.
雫は胸に包んで 届けるよ 空に
I'll wrap the droplets in my heart and deliver them to the sky.
いつでも I love you. 君に Take 2 Kiss me.
Always, I love you. Take 2 kiss me for you.
忘れられないから 僕の大事なメモリー
Because I can't forget, my precious memory.
どら焼きは 主食になれない ならば
Dorayaki can't be a staple food, so...
上書きしちゃえば 僕の思い通り
...if I overwrite it, it'll be just as I want.
夢からピピピさめないで さめないで ぬくもり逃げないで
Please don't wake up from the dream, don't wake up, don't let the warmth escape.
まだあと５分 いや１０分待たせて
Wait for another 5 minutes, no, 10 minutes.
わあ！
Wow!
え？
Eh?
何？
What?
ケーキだ！ケーキだ！
A cake! A cake!
ケーキだ！え、浮いてる！浮いてる！
It's a cake! Eh, it's floating! It's floating!
あ、あ、待って！待って！
Ah, ah, wait! Wait!
行っちゃった。
It's gone.
え、追いかける？
Eh, should we chase it?
あ、そうだね。追いかけよう。
Ah, right. Let's chase it.
行こう！コロネ、待って！
Let's go! Korone, wait!
コロさんいなかったね。
Koro-san wasn't there.
いなかった。
She wasn't.
結構全力で追いかけたんだけど。
We chased after her with all our might.
ねえ。
Yeah.
コロネ早かった。
Korone was fast.
やっぱ足は違う。これでも追いつかなかった。
Her legs are just different after all. Even with this, we couldn't catch up.
これでも猫は？
Even so, as a cat?
猫無理だよ。
It's impossible for a cat.
なんで猫に諦めてんだよ。
Why are you giving up on being a cat?
猫無理。
Cat impossible.
頑張れよ。
Do your best.
猫無理だよ。
It's impossible for a cat.
そんなことないだろ。
That's not true.
無理だよ。
It's impossible.
お前顔どうなってんだよ。
What's up with your face?
絶望してた今。
I was despairing just now.
自分が犬じゃなかったということに絶望した。
I despaired over the fact that I wasn't a dog.
あ、そういうこと。
Ah, I see.
猫も可愛いから大丈夫だよ。
Cats are cute too, so it's okay.
本当？
Really?
可愛い可愛い。
Cute, cute.
じゃあいいかも猫で。
Then maybe it's fine being a cat.
何の話してんだよ。
What are you talking about?
あ、そういえばこの３人といえばさ。
Ah, speaking of these three.
こないだやったさ、歌詞決めオリジナル曲のさ、３人でもあるよね。
We are also the three who did that original song with the lyrics we decided the other day.
そうだね。
That's right.
０デシベル先生、よろしくお願いします。
0-decibel sensei, please.
猫先生です、よろしくお願いします。
I'm Neko sensei, please.
お二人に歌詞を考えていただいたオリジナル楽曲。
An original song with lyrics thought up by these two.
ちょっと今日発表しちゃおうかなーって思っててさ。
I thought I'd announce it today.
イエーイ！
Yay!
（笑い声）
(Laughter)
えー！今の出し方なの、それは！？
Ehh! Is that how you're introducing it!?
そうなの？もう発表しちゃうの？
Really? You're announcing it now?
そうなんだよ。だからちょっとね、今ちょっと歌っちゃわない？
Yeah, that's right. So, why don't we sing it right now?
そんなノリで！？
With that kind of vibe!?
ま、でもやっちゃいますかね、ここはね。
Well, I guess we're doing it then.
猫先生。
Neko-sensei.
先生方に、うん。頑張ってもらって。
Let's do our best, Senseis.
僕たちにかかればね、いけますよ。このぐらいね。
If it's us, we can handle it. This much.
よろしくお願いします、先生方。
Please, Senseis.
まあまあ、君誕生日だもんね。
Well, it is your birthday after all.
あ、そうなんです。誕生日なんです！
Oh, that's right! It is my birthday!
じゃあ、しょうがないからセンターどうぞ。
Then, I guess you take the center.
ありがとうございます！じゃあセンターいただきます。
Thank you very much! I'll take the center then.
じゃあ僕こっち。
I'll be over here.
じゃあ私こっち。位置について。
I'll be this way. Get in position.
ポーズはこれ！
The pose is... this!
あれ？こっち？あれ？
Wait, it's this way? Huh?
ミオしゃ、あっちだよ。
Miosha, it's that way.
あっちだよ、あっちだったわ。
It's that way, I got it wrong.
それでは、オリジナル楽曲…
Well then, here is my original song...
「さしみお」です！
...'Sashimio'!
さしみお feat.スバおか
作詞：立秋（歌詞改変：大空スバル、猫又おかゆ）
作曲・編曲：立秋
Sashimio feat. Suba-Oka
Lyrics: Tachivic (Lyrics rearrangement: Oozora Subaru, Nekomata Okayu)
Composition/Arrangement: Tachivic
うちの名前は大神ミオ！
My name is Ookami Mio!
どこから来たのか あの山の麓！
Where did I come from? The foot of that mountain!
本当は神社の巫女ねーちゃんだ！
Actually, I'm a shrine maiden sister!
みんなを幸せにするぞ！
I'm going to make everyone happy!
今日も一日始まるみょ！
Today starts too, myo!
やみょ！
Yamyo!
おはみおーん！ってどうしたの？
Ohomio-n! What's wrong?
泣いちゃったの？
Are you crying?
そっか、大変だったね。よしよし。
I see, that was tough. There, there.
ああー！これからはそんなことしたらダメだよ。
Aah! You shouldn't do things like that from now on.
今日はおうちに帰ってうちとぼんじり食べよっか。
Let's go home and eat Bonjiri together today.
うち君のために頑張って作っちゃうよ。
I'll work hard to make it for you!
あえー！お兄ちゃん！
Aie! Onii-chan!
なんで他の女の子のことばかり見るの？
Why are you always looking at other girls?
たまにはうちだけ見てほしいみょ！
I want you to only look at me sometimes, myo!
べ、別にあんたのこと好きとかそういうのじゃないけど…
It's not like I like you or anything like that...
うちおかゆも好きっていうか、スバルも好きっていうか…
I mean, I like Okayu too... or rather, I like Subaru too...
つまりその、つまりその…
In other words... in other words...
お刺身ってこと！
It means Sashimi!
真っ直ぐ始まるよ
It's about to start directly
ミオの放送 待機 待機 待機
Mio's broadcast Waiting Waiting Waiting
そろそろお待たせかね
It's almost time for what you've been waiting for
今日もいっぱい笑ってこ！
Let's laugh a lot today too!
セ、タイガァァァァ！
SE-TAIGAAAA!
あえー！うわ！夢か！ってもうこんな時間じゃん！
Aie! Wah! Was it a dream? But it's already this time!
早く学校行かなくちゃ遅刻しちゃうよ！
I have to hurry to school or I'll be late!
仕方がない、パンだけ口に入れてダッシュだ！
Can't be helped, I'll just dash with bread in my mouth!
狼の脚力、なめんなよ！
Don't underestimate a wolf's leg power!
ああー、今日一時間目何だったっけな…
Ah, what was first period today again...?
帰ったら何時から配信やろうかな…
And what time should I start the stream tonight...?
大型企画もそろそろ組みたいしな…
I want to start planning a big project soon, too...
こうやってパンだけ口に入れて走ってると…
Running with bread in my mouth like this...
何か素敵な出会いがあるかもしれないよね！
...maybe I'll have a fateful encounter!
よくあるシチュエーションだと、交差点でドーン！って感じで…
Like a common situation, bumping at an intersection...
いや、でもうち巫女だし、何考えてんだろ！？
Oh no, what am I thinking! I'm a shrine maiden after all!
いたたたたっ！交差点！
Ouch! An intersection!
さしみお！
Sashimio!
わあー！お披露目できたー！
Waaaah! We showed it!
嬉しい、ありがとうー！
I'm so happy, thank you!
いい曲に仕上がってたね！
It turned out to be a really great song!
いい曲だったよー！
It was a good song!
嬉しかった。
So glad.
ね、頑張って歌詞考えてくれて本当にありがとね、二人共！
Thank you so much for working hard on the lyrics, both of you!
こちらこそありがとう！楽しかった！
Likewise, thank you! It was fun!
めちゃ楽しかった！
It was super fun!
立秋さんもね、こんなカオスな曲を…
And Tachivic-sensei, for this chaotic song...
まとめ上げてくださいましたね、立秋先生、ありがとうございます！
...for putting it all together! Thank you very much, Sensei!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
え、この歌はね、後ほど動画でも登場しますのでね。
This song will appear in a video later as well.
えー！そうなの！？
Eh! Is that so!?
楽しみにしててください。
Please look forward to it.
めっちゃ楽しみじゃん！楽しみー！
I'm looking forward to it! Can't wait!
あ、バックダンスもね…
Ah, and the back-dancing...
初めてやったけど、めっちゃ楽しかったよね！
...was my first time, but it was really fun!
楽しかったー！
It was fun!
ここ、ここ！
Right here, right here!
ミミミミミミッミッミ...
Mi mi mi mi mi mi mi...
これが楽しいんだよ！
This is what's fun!
やたら楽しそうだった。
You seemed to be having an awful lot of fun.
カメラさんもちゃんと拾ってくれてたし。
The cameraman was capturing it perfectly, too.
でもカメラさん「どっちが振り向くんだ！？」ってなったでしょ。
But the cameraman must've been like,
"Which one's gonna turn around!?"
どっちかな？
Which one?
こっちか？
This one?
確かに確かに。
True, true.
あー楽しかったね。
Ah, that was fun.
やり切ったわ。
We gave it our all.
ていうかさ、ころさんは？
By the way, where's Koro-san?
あ、あれ？ころさん帰って来なくない？
Oh, wait. Isn't Koro-san coming back?
え、じゃあケーキは？
Eh? Then what about the cake?
あ、もう食べてるかもしれないからさ。
Ah, she might be eating it already.
僕たち先に探しておくよ。
We'll go look for it ahead of you.
え、うちの誕生日ケーキ...
Wait, my birthday cake...
じゃあ！
See ya!
ミオちゃん、ミオちゃん、ここにまだいなさいよ。
Mio-chan, Mio-chan, you stay here for now.
分かった？準備があるでしょう？うちらのライブのね。
Got it? You have prep to do, right? For our live show.
じゃ、スバルたちは一足先にケーキにありつくぜ！
Well, Subaru and the others are gonna
go get that cake first!
待ってよ！ケーキ！
Wait! Cake!
うちのケーキなのに...
Even though it's my cake...
いなくなっちゃった。
They're gone.
でも二人とも、ありがとう！
But thanks to both of you!
じゃ、うちはちょっとゆっくりするか。
Well, I guess I'll relax for a bit.
ウッキー！ミオしゃーん！
Uuuki! Mio-shaan!
よーうしゃ！事務所だってばー！
Yo-sha! I'm telling you, it's the office!
ミオしゃーん！
Mio-shaan!
なんだなんだ、何そのテンション。
What's going on? What's with that energy?
なんかちょっとテンションおかしくない？大丈夫？
Your energy is a bit weird, isn't it? Are you okay?
今日は、今日はなんと...
Today... Today is actually...
お休みの日だけど... イェイイェイイェイ！
My day off, but... Yay yay yay!
なんか誰かいるかなーと思って来ちゃったわけよ。
I thought someone might be here, so I stopped by.
遊びに来たってこと？
You mean you came to play?
そうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
なんで事務所なのにアイドル衣装なの？
Why are you in an idol outfit even though we're in the office?
ああ、ま、ちょっといろいろ海より深い理由が...
Ah, well, for various reasons deeper than the ocean...
海より深いの！？
Deeper than the ocean!?
山より高いってこと？
You mean higher than the mountains?
まあまあまあ、そういうことかな。
Well, well, I guess it's something like that.
え、何してたの？
Eh, what were you doing?
えっ、もうあのね、歌ったりとかしてたんだけどさ。
Eh, well, I was doing things like singing.
ここで？
In here?
まあまあまあ、そうだね。
Well, yeah.
この格好で？
In that outfit?
この格好で。
In this outfit.
うわー、すごいね。
Whoa, that's amazing.
なんか「歌え」って言われて。
I was told to "sing."
あ、歌えって言われたの？
Oh, you were told to sing?
え、トワもミオちゃんと歌いたい！
Eh, Towa wants to sing with Mio-chan too!
え、歌ってくれるの？
Eh, you'll sing with me?
これ誕生日ライブなんだけど大丈夫？
This is a birthday live, though. Is that okay?
あ、じゃあちょっと恥ずかしいからやめとく。
Ah, then I'm a bit embarrassed, so I'll pass.
なんでやねん！
Why not!?
突然やめんな。
Don't suddenly quit on me.
え、ええの？誕生日なのに。
Eh, is it okay? Even though it's my birthday.
トワが出しゃばっていい、みんな？
Is it okay for Towa to barge in, everyone?
イェーイ！歌ってほしい？イェーイ！
Yay! Do you want us to sing? Yay!
じゃあ、せっかくだからトワもアイドル衣装きちゃう？
Then, since we're at it, why don't you
put on an idol outfit too, Towa?
え... やっぱ着るのやめようかな。
Eh... maybe I'll pass on wearing it after all.
なんでやねん！
Why not!?
嘘、着たい！着たい着たい！
Just kidding, I want to! I want to, I want to!
着たいね。じゃあちょっとアイドル衣装ついでにステージも変えちゃおうかな。
You want to, right. Then since we're changing outfits,
let's change the stage too.
お、変えよう変えよう変えよう！
Oh, let's change it, let's change it!
せーの、どん！
One, two, jump!
来ましたよー！
We're here!
来たぜー！イェーイ！
We've arrived! Yay!
というわけでね、可愛い衣装に着替えたところでね。
And so, now that we've changed into cute outfits.
緊張してきた！
I'm getting nervous!
緊張してきた？
You're getting nervous?
何歌うか知ってる？
Do you know what we're going to sing?
知ってるよ。
I know.
知ってた。
I knew it.
テレパシーで通じちゃった。
We connected via telepathy.
なんだその間は。
What was with that pause?
ちょっとあのいい感じの大人の魅力を出してみた。
I was trying to project some of that 'adult charm.'
あ、そういうこと？大人の魅力じゃあちょっと頑張って追求していく歌なのかな？
Ah, is that it? So is it a song where we have
to work on our adult charm?
分かんないけど。
I don't know though.
いや、ちゃうわ。
No, that's not it.
違うかい！
It's not!?
ちょっとあのハッピーな感じで行くかな。
I think we'll go with a happy vibe.
ハッピーな感じでね。イェーイイェーイ！じゃあみんな盛り上がっていきましょう！
With a happy vibe, right. Yay yay!
Then everyone, let's get hyped!
というわけで、次で二人で歌う曲いっちゃいましょうか！
So, let's go with the next song we'll sing together!
おい！
Hey!
せーの！BLUE CLAPPER！
One, two! BLUE CLAPPER!
手を上げて Clap your hands / 生み出す航路まで Clap your hands
Raise your hands and clap your hands /
To the course that we create, clap your hands
届きますように
I hope it reaches you
手を叩こう 手を叩こう ほら一緒に
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands,
come on, together
Everybody Clap your hands / 空に響く方まで Clap your hands
Everybody clap your hands /
Until it reaches the sky, clap your hands
響きますように
I hope it resonates
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す僕たちの未来
The light shines on our future
Hi! Ho! 4
High! Ho! 4
1 トワ様降臨！
1 Towa-sama has arrived!
始めようか Get ready 待っても意味ないタイミング
Shall we begin? Get ready,
there's no point in waiting for the timing
あの魚みたいに Swimming swimming
Like that fish, swimming swimming
引き寄せる Lighting まだ見えない
Drawing in the lighting, still can't see it
Hey maybe 今この瞬間に何があるの？
Hey maybe, what is there in this moment?
待ったはないの提灯　追いつくまでshaking
There's no waiting, keep shaking until I catch up
でもたまに止まってthinking thinking
But sometimes I stop to keep on thinking, thinking
変えてみせるぜ運気　踏み出すのは3step
I'll change my luck, starting with these three steps
掴んでみせるよ　キラキラMy dream
I'll grasp it, my sparkling dream
叶う日までStory
Until the day it comes true, this is my story
繋ぐから　だって君に
I'll connect it, because I want you...
ずっと見てほしいから
...to keep watching me forever
手を挙げてClap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands and clap, to the other side of the sea
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, so it reaches you
手を叩こう　手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら一緒に
Come on, join in
Everybody Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, to the other side of the sky
Clap your hands 響きますように
Clap your hands, so it resonates
手を叩こう　手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す　僕たちの未来
The light shines on our future
昼間いらないbreak it 理性は早めにbreak it
No need for the day, break it; break your reason early
何時でも良いでしょう？ 24/7
Any time is fine, right? 24/7
君は何をfeel it？ 解き放てsparking
What are you feeling? Let it all out sparking
暗闇に放つレーザービーム
A laser beam firing into the darkness
光らせてステージ
Light up the stage
作るから　だって君に
I'll create it, because I want you...
もっと見てほしいから
...to watch me even more
手を挙げてClap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands and clap, to the other side of the sea
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, so it reaches you
手を叩こう　手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら一緒に
Come on, join in
Everybody Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, to the other side of the sky
Clap your hands 響きますように
Clap your hands, so it resonates
手を叩こう　手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
重なるwave 世界を揺らせ
Overlapping waves, let them shake the world
終わりあることすら　既にI know
I already know that everything has an end
でもまだまだ泳ぎ足りないの
But I still haven't had enough of swimming through it
Boom Give me crazy
Boom 窓はracy
Boom, the window is racy
Boom 次元勝り合う 全て塗り替えるよ
Boom, outdoing the dimensions, I'll repaint it all
手を挙げてClap your hands 海の向こうまで
Raise your hands and clap, to the other side of the sea
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, so it reaches you
手を叩こう　手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら一緒に
Come on, join in
Everybody Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Everybody clap your hands, to the other side of the sky
Clap your hands 響きますように
Clap your hands, so it resonates
手を叩こう　手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す　僕たちの未来
The light shines on our future
はぁー！
Phew!
はぁ、激しい...
Wow, that was intense...
BLUE CLAPPERでした！
That was BLUE CLAPPER!
でした！
It was!
あぁ、ありがとう！いや、すごい楽しかった！
Ah, thank you! Man, that was so much fun!
楽しかった！
It was fun!
疲れたんじゃないかい？
You must be tired, right?
いやー、でも楽しかった。
Yeah, but it was fun.
お休み中なのに、ごめんね、来てもらって。
Sorry for having you come over even though you're on break.
いや全然！もう、ミオちゃんが呼ぶならもう行きますよ！
No, not at all! If Mio-chan calls, I'll be there!
羽を広げ、ミオちゃんのもとへ。
Spreading my wings... to Mio-chan's side.
なるほどね、羽を広げ。
I see, spreading your wings.
そうそうそう。
Right, right.
あ、てかそういえばさ、なんでミオちゃんさ、事務所にいたの？
Oh, speaking of which, why were you at the office, Mio-chan?
あぁ、そうだ。ケーキ食べようと思ってたんだけど...
Oh, that's right. I was planning to eat cake, but...
あぁ、ケーキね！あ！ハッピーバースデー、ミオちゃん！
Ah, cake! Oh! Happy Birthday, Mio-chan!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
I love you!
そう、そうなんだけど...アイラブユー。
Yeah, that's right... I love you too.
アイラブユー！
I love you!
そう、そうなんだけどさぁ、なんか、ケーキなくて。
Yeah, but the thing is, there's no cake.
あぁ、なんかどっかでケーキ見なかった？
Oh, didn't you see a cake somewhere?
あ、ケーキ？え、結構大きかった？
Oh, cake? Um, was it quite big?
あ、そう！大きいケーキ！見た？
Ah, yes! A big cake! Did you see it?
見たかもしれない！
I might have seen it!
え、本当！？
Really!?
え、ちょっと行こうか？探しに。ちょっと行ってくるわ！
Well, shall we go look for it? I'll go check!
え、トワ様！？おー、わかった！行ってらっしゃい！
Eh, Towa-sama!? Oh, okay! Take care!
ありがとう！え、なんか、え、教えて、どこにあったか！
Thank you! Wait, um, tell me where it was!
いなくなっちゃった。
She's gone.
え、ケーキあったみたいですね。っていうことは、うちはもうちょっとでケーキが食べれるってこと？
Oh, it seems there was a cake. Does that mean I'll be able to eat cake soon?
わかんないけど。え？何？何？この声は？この舌足らずな声は？
I'm not sure, but... Eh? What? What's that? This voice? This lisping voice?
は！みこち！
Ah! Mikochi!
は！待ってた、それはケーキ！
Wait, that's the cake!
あ、ちょっとちょっとちょっと！ほら、なんで持ち逃げしようとしてるの？
Ah, wait wait wait! Look, why are you trying to run away with it?
いや、これはね、ちょっとさっき、あの、そこら辺にね、こうやって置いてあったから、みこキャッチしたんだよ。
Well, you see, it was just sitting over there earlier, so Miko caught it.
あ、置いてあったの？なんかひどい...
Oh, it was just left there? How mean...
拾ってきたってこと？
You mean you picked it up?
いや、これは拾ってきたというのもそうなんだけど...
Well, it's true I picked it up, but...
すごい言い訳するじゃん。
You're making a lot of excuses.
みおちゃんに、あの、誕生日プレゼントでいいかなと思ってちょっと... 拾ってきたな。
I thought it'd be good as a birthday present for Mio-chan, so I... picked it up.
本当？ありがとう、嬉しい！
Really? Thank you, I'm happy!
もしかして、これは初めて見たケーキではないってこと？
Wait, does this mean this isn't the first time I've seen this cake?
お、なんかね... なんかずーっとお預けくらってるんだよ、ケーキ。
Oh, well... I've been kept waiting for a cake for so long.
あ、そうなの？じゃあ、みこが持ってきたげて...
Oh, really? Then Miko brought it for you...
やったー！
Yay!
みこち大好き、ありがとう！
I love you, Mikochi! Thank you!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
じゃあ、二人でケーキ食べちゃう？
Then, shall we eat the cake together?
あ、食べよう！
Oh, let's eat!
みおも食べていいの？
Can I eat it too?
もちろん、もちろん。
Of course, of course.
ちょっとね... どこに行ったのかな？とはなんかずっと思ってたの。
I was wondering where it had gone all this time.
あ、言ってたね。
Ah, you were saying that.
そう、ケーキがなんかあるって言って、どっか行っちゃったんだけどさ。
Yeah, someone said there was a cake, but then it disappeared.
なんか、どこにもいなくなっちゃったんだよね。
It was just nowhere to be found.
みこ、なんかフォークとか...
Miko, like, forks and stuff...
うん、ここにあるのにね。
Yeah, even though it's right here.
なかなかちょっと... いや...
It's a bit... well...
ケーキ、せっかくだからね、食べたいから、このチャンスを逃す手はないんだけど。
Since we have the cake, I want to eat it. No way I'm missing this chance.
そうだね。じゃあ、ここに一旦置く？
True. Shall we put it down here for a moment?
あ、置いとこうか。よいしょ。
Oh, let's do that. There we go.
いやー、いいんね！可愛いよね、ケーキね。
Wow, it's nice! The cake is cute, isn't it?
ね、美味しそうだね。
Yeah, looks delicious.
あ、ケーキ...
Ah, the cake...
大丈夫、みおちゃん。すごい誕生日おめでとう、みおちゃん。
It's okay, Mio-chan. A very happy birthday to you, Mio-chan.
ありがとう！歌って踊ると結構ゼーゼー... あ、あせ...
Thank you! Singing and dancing makes me quite out of breath... and sweaty...
そう、なんか色々あったのかな。よいしょ、よいしょ。すごい労い対応。
Yeah, I guess a lot happened. There we go. Such hard-working service.
ちょっとね、あの、嬉しい気持ちが... あれ？
Well, my happy feelings are... wait?
おっほっほー！
Ohohoho!
なんだ？魔王みたいな笑い方して。
What's that? Laughing like a demon king.
トワ様の声。
It's Towa-sama's voice.
はーい！今からトワ様がお送りする、食レポクイズ！
Hi! Now, Towa-sama presents: The Food Report Quiz!
食レポクイズ！セルフSE。
Food Report Quiz! Self-made sound effects.
（パチパチパチ）
(Clapping)
ケーキを、食べたいか？
Do you want... to eat cake?
食べたいよ！お腹すいたよ！誕生日だからね！
We want to! We're hungry! It's a birthday after all!
ケーキを、食べたいのであれば、トワの食レポのゲームに正解したならば良いです。
If you want to eat cake, then it's fine if you answer Towa's food report game correctly.
噛みましたね。
You stumbled over your words.
みこ死なな？
Miko won't die, right?
ミコ先輩は、死ぬ。
Miko-senpai... will die.
なんで！？なんでみこだけ死ぬのおかしいだろ！おかしいだろ！
Why?! Why only Miko? That's not right! That's not right!
聞いてきたから。もう聞いてきたから、もうみこちが答えようかなみたいな。
Because you asked. Since you asked, maybe Mikochi should be the one to answer.
なるほど。
I see.
何クイズって言った？
What kind of quiz did you say?
食レポクイズです。
A food report quiz.
食レポできんの？トワ様。
Can you even do a food report, Towa-sama?
いや、できるよ。
Of course I can.
へー、本当に？うまいんだ。
Oh, really? You're good at it.
今日はね、ライン超えしない程度に食レポしていきたいと思います。
Today, I'll do a food report without crossing the line.
食レポでライン超えって逆にどうやってやるの？
How do you even cross the line with a food report?
どういうことなんだ一体。
What on earth does that mean?
トワ、ちょっと語彙力が足りなすぎて、トワの小さい辞書から引きずり出した...
Towa's vocabulary is a bit lacking, so I've dragged words out from my tiny dictionary...
小さい辞書。
A tiny dictionary.
今頑張ってる。そういうこと。
I'm trying hard right now. That's how it is.
今トワの目の前には、もうあるんです。食材が。
Right in front of Towa, there it is. The ingredient.
あ、これから食レポする食材があるってこと？
Oh, so you have the ingredient you're going to report on?
そうなんです。トワは部屋で一人ぼっちでこの食材を食べて、皆さんにお知らせをすると。
That's right. Towa is alone in her room, eating this ingredient and reporting to everyone.
今ぼっちなの？一人ぼっちなんだ、トワ様。誰もいないんだ。誰もいないんだ。
Are you alone right now? You're all alone, Towa-sama? No one's there? No one's there?
誰もいないです。誰の反応もなしに生きてます。はい。
No one. I'm living without anyone's reaction. Yes.
なんかちょっぴりかわいそう。
That's a bit sad.
じゃあ、早速だけど、始めてもらっていい？ケーキ食べたいし。
Then, can you start right away? We want to eat cake.
食べたい。
We want to eat.
じゃあ、やりたいと思います。お願いします。
Okay, then I'll do it. Here goes.
いやー、まず、てか、何でこんなちょっと地獄なんだけど。なんか手が震えてるんだけど。
Wow, first of all, why is this like hell? My hands are shaking.
なんで！？トワ様。
Why?! Towa-sama.
まず一ついきたいと思います。
First, I'll take one (bite).
何？どんなものが来んの？
What? What's coming?
あ、食べてる、食べてる。味わってるにゃ。
Ah, I'm eating, eating. I'm savoring it.
ご馳走様？
Is she finished?
まずそうですね、えっと... あ、食べてるにゃ。
First, let's see... um... Ah, I'm eating.
天使のような。
Like an angel.
天使？ふわふわな？
An angel? Fluffy?
ふわふわな、かなたんってこと？
Fluffy... you mean like Kanatan?
いや、もう、それはゴリラや。あ、ゴリラじゃなかった。
No, she's a gorilla. Ah, not a gorilla.
かなたんが見てるよ、絶対！大丈夫？ニヤニヤしてるから。
Kanatan is definitely watching! Is that okay? She's smirking.
ふわふわな、そうですね、あの、布団と布団の間に...
Fluffy... well, um, like between blankets...
布団と布団の間に？
Between blankets?
そうですね、あの、程よい甘さの... そうですね、あの... 雲も、雲も。
Well, um, with a moderate sweetness... well, um... Clouds, too, clouds.
ほうほう。
I see, I see.
何て言えばいいんですか、あの、雲も雲が入ってて。
How should I put it... um, clouds, clouds are in it.
ほう。
Oh.
これ、味で言うともう本当に何て言うんだろう。
If I were to describe the taste... how should I say it.
雲が入ってる？
Clouds are in it?
恋の香り、あ、違う。恋のなんて言うんだろう。
The scent of love... no, wait. The... of love, what's it called.
恋の？
Of love?
もう、うん、あの、青春を思い出すような... 下手なんですけど、食レポ。
Well, yeah, um, it reminds you of your youth... Your food report is terrible.
人のせいにしないで！私が受け取ったもんだもん。
Don't blame it on me! I'm just the one who received it.
で、あのふわふわのお布団の間に、その青春のなんか、
And, between those fluffy futons, that youthful something...
味はその青春のような、うーん、その、もう、もうそういうことよ。
...the flavor is like youth, um, well, that's just how it is.
で、なるほど！わかったわかった！
And, I see! I got it, I got it!
何、何？
What is it?
あと、あとは、え、いいよ、みこ先輩。
Also, next... oh, go ahead, Miko-senpai.
食レポま！
Food report-ma!
あーちゃうちゃうちゃうちゃう。え、違うんだ？
Ah, no no no no. Oh, it's not?
ちゃうちゃう。お布団とお布団というかね、
No no. Like, futon and futon.
いやまあまあ、あ、じゃあわかったわかった！はいはいはい！
Well, okay, then I got it! Yes, yes!
ショートケーキ！ショートケーキ！
Shortcake! Shortcake!
あーちゃうちゃうちゃうちゃう！ちゃうのかよ！
Ah, no no no no! Is it not?!
じゃなくて、ちょっと聞いて！
Not that, listen for a second!
その間に、その間に、もうぴちぴちの、
In between those, in between those, very fresh...
南国のような、そういうなんか、もう、はじける感じのものが、
Like the tropical south, that kind of popping feeling thing...
はじける感じ？！
A popping feeling?!
お布団の間に！なんだろう？
...between the futons! What could it be?
そうそうそう、その青春のような感じのがそこでギュッと。
Yes yes yes, that youthful feeling is packed tight in there.
え、どういうことだよ？何何何？
Wait, what do you mean? What what what?
ぴちぴちはじけるって何？
What's this about fresh and popping?
うまいやろ？
Good, right?
終わったってこと？終わったのかもしれない。
You mean it's over? It might be over.
嘘？！外れたってこと？！外れたってことかもしれない。
No way! Does that mean we missed it? It might mean you missed it.
え、他に何か言わなくていいの？
Wait, don't you have anything else to say?
え、じゃあ、みこマンゴープリン！
Um, then... Miko says mango pudding!
はい、ということでね、おい！ダメ！ダメ！
Alright, so... Hey! No! No!
はい、ということでじゃないわ。はい、ということで、
Well, anyway, yes, anyway...
まあ、誰も正解しなかったけど、
Well, nobody got it right, but...
正解は、正解はフルーツサンドでした！
The answer... the answer was a fruit sandwich!
フルーツサンド？！？！
Fruit sandwich?!
いやまあ、甘、ね、あの恋の感じが出てたでしょう？
Well, it's sweet, and that feeling of love was there, right?
出てねえよ！恋の感じって！
No it wasn't! What "feeling of love"!
あ、出てねえか。
Ah, it wasn't?
いや、でもケーキはちょっと無理だ。あげられない。
Well, but the cake is a no-go. I can't give it to you.
あ、そうか。ケーキはそう、失敗したからね。あげられません！残念！
Ah, I see. Since you failed with the cake, I can't give it to you! Too bad!
そうなの？みおぱぱもダメなの？えー残念。
Is that so? Mio-papa can't have it either? Aww, too bad.
じゃ、ケーキはみこもらっちゃいまーす！さよなら！ありがとう！
Then Miko will take the cake. Goodbye! Thank you!
没収ってこと？！没収です！待っててー！
You mean it's confiscated? Confiscated! Wait for me!
ひどい！ひどいよー！
That's terrible! So mean!
ケーキ食わせろー！誕生日だぞー！
Let me eat the cake! It's my birthday!
せーのでした。ごめんねみおちゃん、みこが正解すれば食べられたかもしれないのに。
That's how it went. Sorry Mio-chan, if only Miko had gotten it right, we could've eaten it.
うーん、ごめんね、みんな。でもマンゴープリンは違うだろう。
Sorry everyone. But mango pudding was definitely wrong.
いやそうかもしれないけど、うんうん、はい。
Well, that might be true... yeah, yeah, okay.
え、というわけでね、我々不正解だったので、
Anyway, since we were wrong...
ケーキは残念ながら食べれないんだけど、曲も出ない。
...unfortunately we can't eat the cake, and the song won't play either.
あーそうなんだよ。でもさ、せっかく来てくれたからさ、
Yeah, that's right. But since you're here...
歌いたいんだけど、一緒に。
...I'd like to sing together.
え！みこも歌いたい！やったー！
Eh! Miko wants to sing too! Yay!
嬉しい嬉しい！歌おう！
I'm so happy! Let's sing!
というわけで、じゃあちょっと、はい、何ですか？歌いたい！
So, um, yes, what is it? I want to sing!
はい、承知しました。はいはい。なるほどね。おけおけ。
Yes, I understand. I see. Okay okay.
じゃあ皆さんに、じゃあ二人で歌う曲、一応聞いてるかな？
So, do you know the song we're going to sing together?
聞いてる！
I do!
お！じゃあ二人で、うん。じゃあこの曲、「せーの」って言ったら「せーの」で言ってくれる？
Oh! Then the two of us... yeah. Then, when I say "one-two", can you say it too?
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
じゃあ二人でこの曲歌います！せーの！
Then the two of us will sing this song! One-two!
POPPY PAPPY DAY!
星キラキラ
Twinkling stars
いつか二人で
Someday, the two of us
夢の舞台
On the stage of dreams
手を広げ
Spread our arms
中指
Middle finger
POPPY PAPPY DAY
作詞・作曲：BUSTED ROSE
Lyrics/Music: BUSTED ROSE
立てるんだ
Raising it up
退屈な世界
Boring world
これからも一緒だよ
We'll be together from now on too
ずっとずっと
Forever and ever
仲良し小良しの二人 二人だ
The two of us are great friends, the two of us
POPPY PAPPY DAY
可愛かった！満足満足！
That was cute! I'm satisfied!
イェーイ！あ、ケーキが！
Yay! Ah, the cake!
あ！ケーキの！
Ah! The cake is!
おおお！やばい！みんなやばい！ちょっと二人でさ、内緒でさ、
Whoa! This is bad! Everyone, this is bad! Let's just the two of us, in secret...
食べちゃおう！食べちゃおう！トワもいないし！
Let's eat it! Let's eat it! Towa isn't here either!
じゃ、みおちゃん、またねー！
Then, Mio-chan, see ya!
え、どういうこと？！ちょっと待って！
Wait, what? Wait a second!
あばよ！ありがとう！
Later! Thanks!
ありがとうだけど、なんでなんでなんで？！
Thanks, but why why why?!
食べながら去ってったんだけど！何であんなの？！ちょっと！
They left while eating it! Why would they do that?! Hey!
ちょっと、食べながら、食べながら去ってったんだけど……
Hey, they left while eating it... they really did...
ううう……オチも。結局ケーキは今回食べられませんでした。
Uuu... even the punchline. In the end, I couldn't eat the cake this time.
というわけでね
Anyway...
えー皆さん、誕生日のライブいかがでしたでしょうか？
Everyone, how did you like the birthday live?
楽しんでもらえましたか？
Did you have fun?
ここでですね、あの少し告知をさせていただきたいと思うんですけれども
Now, I'd like to make a small announcement...
みんな良いでしょうか？
Is everyone ready?
良いかー？
Are you ready?
はい。
Yes.
すごく楽しかった、うんうん、
It was very fun, yeah, yeah,
良かった良かった。
good, good.
あーいいよ。
Ah, it's okay.
オッケー、ありがとうありがとう。
Okay, thank you, thank you.
というわけで、なんと誕生日記念グッズが発売されるので、
So, surprisingly, birthday commemorative goods are going on sale,
こちらご覧ください。ドーン！
so please take a look at this. Bam!
はい、えー、誕生日記念セットです。
Yes, this is the birthday commemorative set.
こちらはですね、グッズが5つ付いてきまして、
This comes with five items,
大神ミオミニアルバム「Howling」。
Ookami Mio's mini-album, "Howling."
なんとですね、今回オリジナル曲がマジメなやつ出るんですけど、それが「Howling」というタイトルなので
Actually, a serious original song is coming out this time, and its title is "Howling"...
こちらですね、はい。ミニアルバムこちらを、えー、3曲収録されております。
So this mini-album contains three songs.
こちらよかったら、大神ミオ特製複製メッセージ入りミニカードも入っておりますので、
It also includes a mini-card with a special replica message from Ookami Mio,
ぜひぜひこちらもチェックしてみてください。
so please check it out.
そして、この5つの中の色々紹介してくんだけど、
And I'll introduce the various items among these five...
まずは、ジャケットポスター。
First, the jacket poster.
これは泉パパに描いてもらったイラストになってます。はい。
This illustration was drawn by Izumi-papa. Yes.
そしてCDなんだけど、そのCDが、表面はこの「Howling」の、
About the CD, the front side features this "Howling" art...
めちゃくちゃかっこいいよね。そうなんだよ、泉パパがすごいスピードで描いてくれたこのイラストめちゃくちゃかっこいいんです。
It's so cool. Yeah, Izumi-papa drew this illustration very quickly, and it's super cool.
このジャケットイラスト、プラス、裏面のジャケ裏は、
This jacket illustration, plus the back cover...
えー、先程
the back cover is...
歌った曲の、はい、こちらですね、
for the song I just sang, yes, this one...
えー、パンジャメのなめ先生に書いていただいた、えー、イラストになります。
it's an illustration by Pan-jam-no-name-sensei.
うちがワンワンワンワン言ってる曲になります。はい。パンジャメのなめ先生ありがとうございます。はい。
It's for the song where I go "woof woof woof woof". Thank you, Pan-jam-no-name-sensei.
そして、えー、次は、こちらジャケットポスターですね。
And next is the jacket poster.
こちらも付いておりますので、ぜひお部屋に飾ってください。
This is also included, so please display it in your room.
お次、こちら、アクリルジオラマスタンドということで、えー、なんとこちらですね
Next is the acrylic diorama stand, and for this one...
背景、そして地面があって、
there's a background and a floor,
こう海にうちがこう浮き輪で浮いてて、
I'm floating in the sea on an inner tube,
後ろの水しぶき、
with water splashing behind me,
そしてタワちゃんとタイガ、およびスバルのアヒルが全部バラバラになってて、
and Tawa-chan, Taiga, and Subaru's duck are all separate pieces...
こう奥行きのあるアクリルスタンドになってます。これも泉パパが書いてくれました。泉パパ大活躍。ありがとう。すごい可愛いイラストだよ。はい。
making it an acrylic stand with depth. Izumi-papa drew this too. Izumi-papa is doing great. Thank you. It's a very cute illustration.
そして次はですね、こちら、えー、かもちょめ先生のイラスト、
And next is an illustration by Kamo-chome-sensei,
いつもね動くイラスト描いてくださってるかもちょめ先生に書いていただいた、ラバーキーホルダー。
the rubber keychain drawn by Kamo-chome-sensei who always draws moving illustrations for me.
こちらがですね、なんとボイスが出るんです。
This one actually plays voices.
これねポチッと押すとね、あの5種類のボイスがランダムで出るっていうキーホルダーになってまして、
When you press it, one of five different voices will play randomly.
今日持ってこようと思ったんだけど、ちょっと忘れちゃって
I thought about bringing it today, but I forgot.
ね、その中には、え、もよよよみみみみだとか、
In there are lines like "Moyoyoyo mimimimi" or...
あとは、お刺身ってこと？とか、そういうようなうちの、うちらしい言葉が5種類入ってます。
“Is it sashimi?”, five kinds of very “me” phrases are included.
よかったらみんな押して楽しんでみてください。結構音大きいので。
Please enjoy pressing it. The sound is quite loud.
あの周りにいっぱい人がいるときとかは結構みんなはってなっちゃうかもしれないけど、はい。ぜひこれはぜひぜひゲットしてほしい品です。はい。
If you use it when there are many people around, they might be surprised. This is definitely an item I want you to get.
お次の品。はいこちら、え、ミオの部屋着とおそろロングTシャツ。パフパフ。
Next item. This is the "Matching Long T-shirt with Mio's Room-wear". Puff puff.
これはね、絶対出したかったんだよね。
I definitely wanted to release this.
これはね、LサイズとXLサイズの2サイズ展開となってまして、
It comes in two sizes, L and XL.
うちがねあのパーカーの下に着ている、
It's based on what I wear under my hoodie...
えーっと、なんていうの？部屋着みたいなやつなんだけど、
what do you call it? Like room-wear.
これを、あの男の人も着れるようにデザインをね、あのシンプルにさせてもらって、
I designed it to be simple so that men can also wear it,
作らせてもらいました。
so I had it made.
はい。こちらみんなね、うちとおそろいの部屋着にしてもらってもいいですし、
You can use it as matching room-wear with me...
これだったらねシンプルなんでお外に着ていってもねかっこいいんじゃないかなって思います。
or since it's simple, I think it would look cool to wear outside too.
ぜひいっぱい着てください。そしてお次。
Please wear it a lot. And next.
え、フルセットを購入いただくと、え、こちらの泉パパのジオラマアクリルスタンドのイラストのポストカード付いてきます。
If you buy the full set, you'll get a postcard with Izumi-papa's diorama acrylic stand illustration.
うちの箔押しサインが入って、あとはメッセージも複製で入ってるので、ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
It has my foil-stamped signature and a printed message, so please check it out.
というわけで、以上グッズの紹介でした。
So, that was the introduction of the goods.
でした。長い時間ありがとうございました。
That's all. Thank you for the long time.
そして、BOOTHのページは
And, the BOOTH page
22時からオープンして、
will open at 22:00,
購入開始は22時10分からなので、
and sales start at 22:10,
あ、もう購入が多分スタートしてる形なんですかね？
so, ah, maybe the sales have already started?
多分ね、あの概要欄が更新すると
Probably, once the description is updated,
概要欄にあのBOOTHのURLとか出てくると思うんですけど、はい。
the BOOTH URL and such will appear in the description, yes.
URL更新すると出るので
It'll show up after the URL update.
もしくはあのホロライブの公式グッズはこちらっていうURLから飛べますので
Or you can go from the "Hololive Official Goods Here" URL,
是非皆さんチェックしてみて下さい。
so please everyone check it out.
バラバラでも売ってます。
They are also sold individually.
はい。そして最後にうちがもう一曲オリジナル曲を披露させていただきたいんですが、
Yes. And finally, I'd like to perform one more original song,
そちらの曲の紹介も少しさせていただきます。
so I'll also introduce that song a little.
「Howling」という曲なんですが、
It's a song called "Howling",
まず、え、作詞、作詞作曲をしてくださった方のご紹介をさせていただきます。
and first, I'll introduce the person who wrote the lyrics and composed it.
あ、もう買った？みんな。ありがとありがと。
Oh, you already bought it? Everyone. Thanks, thanks.
はい。それではスライドお願いします。
Yes. Now, slides please.
はい、え、ZAQ（ざっく）さんという「中二病でも恋がしたい！」という作品の
Yes, ZAQ-san, who has created the
オープニング主題歌や、
opening theme for "Love, Chunibyo & Other Delusions!"
え、映画のオープニング主題歌も作っていらっしゃる
and also for movies.
まああのね、結構女性の方で、凄くキャッチーなメロディーを作るのが
Well, she's a woman who is very good at creating catchy melodies
凄いキラキラした楽曲サウンドを作るのが得意な方なんですけど、
and sparkling music sounds,
知ってる方もきっといるよね。
so I'm sure some of you know her.
あ、ZAQさん知ってる知ってる。あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, you know ZAQ-san. Ah, I see.
いや本当にもうこの曲を書いていただいた時に、凄い最初、
Honestly, when she wrote this song for me, right from the start
もう最初の方から「うわ、すごい。すごい天才的」みたいな
I thought, "Wow, this is amazing. Truly genius,"
本当いい曲だなって思ったので
and it's such a great song.
みんなに早く聴いて欲しくて、ずっと匂わせてました。
I wanted everyone to hear it soon, so I've been hinting at it for a while.
はい、というわけで、うちが最後にHowlingを披露させていただきまして、
Yes, and so, I'll perform "Howling" at the end,
今回は誕生日ライブ終わりにしたいと思います。
and that will be the end of this birthday live.
それでは聴いてください。うちのオリジナル楽曲になります。
Now, please listen. This is my original song.
Howling！
Howling!
静寂に　響いてよ　My howling
Echo in the silence, my howling
とうとうと　流れてゆく光景
A scene flowing endlessly,
切な的な　日々の中で
amidst transient days
差し伸べられた手は優しく
The hand reached out was gentle,
鼓動に滴る微熱の予感
a premonition of slight fever dripping into my heartbeat
風に逆らう　そう生きてきたから
Living while defying the wind,
君に会って気づく
I realized upon meeting you
もう独りじゃない
that I'm not alone anymore
遮光　瞬きは声掻き消し
Blocking light, blinking drowns out voices,
響く　つまびく未知
echoing, plucking at the unknown,
孤高の群れ　共に嘆く夜
a solitary pack, a night of mourning together
慟哭　伝播する想いは
Lamentation, propagating feelings
心強くする　付いておいでよ
make the heart strong. Come along,
後ろに君がいるから　私は迷わない
because you're behind me, I won't falter
光射す道へ
towards the path of light
無力だから仲間を求め
Seeking companions because of powerlessness,
凍えるから　灯をともして
lighting a lamp because of the cold
変化と共に進化してく
Evolving along with change,
この結末は誰も知らない
no one knows this conclusion
君を信じる　そう決めているから
Because I've decided to believe in you,
どんな異常事態も　乗り越えられるよ
I can overcome any abnormal situation
月光　この闇に唯一り
Moonlight, alone in this darkness,
毒々しく花
a venomous flower,
畏れなのか　憧れなのか　向かい合う夜空
fear, or longing? Facing the night sky
大地を　駆け抜ける私と
The story created by
君が創り出す　この物語
you and me, running through the earth
単純な未来じゃない　沸き立つ情熱
Not a simple future, seething passion,
放て　声にだせよ
let it out, speak up
空飛ぶ羽なくても
Even without wings to fly,
手は繋げられたから
we could hold hands,
この運命を...
so this destiny...
...るんだ
...believe.
伝播する熱を
The propagating heat...
覚えは真芯に響いて
...the memory resonates in my core.
何度も何度もその絆を確かめあった
Time and again, we confirmed that bond.
あまねく時は声高く月へ響く
In times universal, my voice rings out loud to the moon.
爪弾きし孤高の群れ 共に嘆くよ
The ostracized, solitary pack laments together.
慟哭 伝播する思いは心強くする
Lamentation; these propagating feelings make me stronger.
共にいこうよ 隣に君がいるから
Let's go together, because you are by my side.
私も迷わない 光さす道へ
I won't hesitate either, toward the path of light.
Listen to my howling...
狼が止まることはない
The wolf will never stop.
大神ミオ たんじょうび3Dライブ
だけど... クイズやゲームあり？！
8月20日21時～
Ookami Mio Birthday 3D Live
But... there will be quizzes and games?!
August 20th from 21:00
みんな、ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you very much!